now let's briefly consider just what
happens to load and store instructions
just like we had data dependencies that
go through registers this is for example
why we did register raming to eliminate
the false dependencies through registers
and why we are doing uh these
reservation stations and so on in order
to kind of obey properly the true
dependencies there can be dependencies
through memory because loads and stores
in this case are the only instructions
that can have dependencies through
memory but there can be dependencies a
read after write dependence occurs
if there is for example a store word to
some address in memory and then we do a
load word from that address then there
is definitely a read after write
dependence between the store and the
load basically the load uses the value
put there by the store we can also have
a right after read false dependence for
example we can have the program that
first needs to load something then store
it if we reorder these then the load
gets a value from the store not the
value from before and finally we can
have a right after right depend if there
are two stores that store to the same
address the last one should kind of
leave the value at the end of that
sequence but if we reorder them then the
value in the memory ends up being the
kind of stale value from the first of
the stores so obviously dependencies
through memory need to be obeyed or
eliminated just like the registered ones
do so what do we do about this
dependencies in tomasulo's algorithm we
do loads and stores in order basically
we don't try to reorder them when as we
issue these instructions we put them in
the load or a sore queue and then we
just follow the order of these
instructions so for example a load
doesn't execute if there is a previous
store pending even though maybe the load
is ready to go but the store still is
waiting for something the second option
is to actually identify dependencies
between load stores Etc and then reorder
them just like we did normal
instructions Etc but this turns out to
be more complicated than doing it for
register BAS dependencies so we're not
going to do that and that's why for
tomasulo's algorithm they chose not to
do this for memory instructions but they
chose to do do it for other instructions
modern processors actually do identify
dependencies reorder Etc even for loads
and stores but uh we will consider later
how that is done so so for tomasulo's
algorithm this was really kind of the
you know option that they chose